nuclino.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy | Nuclino

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) governs and describes how Nuclino GmbH and its subsidiaries (“Nuclino”, “we,” “us” or “our”) may collect, use, and disclose personal information when you use our products or services, or otherwise interact with Nuclino (for example, attending Nuclino events), unless a different privacy policy is displayed. This policy also explains your choices about how we use information about you. Your choices include how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you. If you do not agree with this policy, do not access or use our Services or interact with any other aspect of our business.

Nuclino offers collaborative tools, including our web, desktop, and mobile products, which help users to collaborate with others. We also own and operate a number of websites and offer related services, like support. We refer to all of these products, together with our other services and websites as "Services" in this policy.

We have updated this Privacy Policy in order to comply with changes in data protection law. In addition, we have worked to make the Privacy Policy clearer and more understandable.

## What we explain in this policy

  * What information we collect about you

  * How we use the information

  * How we share the information

  * How we store and secure the information

  * How to access and control your information

  * How we transfer the information we collect internationally

  * Other important privacy-related information

## What information we collect about you

### Information you provide to us

  *  _Account and profile information:_ We collect information about you when you register for an account, create or modify your profile, set preferences, sign-up for or make purchases through the Services. For example, this includes your first name, last name, email address, profile picture, and notification settings.

  *  _Content you provide through the Services:_ Using Nuclino may involve creating, editing, and sharing content. For example, this includes the name and content of teams, workspaces, items, and clusters.

  *  _Information you provide through our support channels:_ The Services also include customer support, where you may choose to submit information regarding a problem you are experiencing with a Service. Whether you contact customer support via email, speak to one of our representatives directly or otherwise engage with our support team, you will be asked to provide contact information, a summary of the problem you are experiencing, and any other documentation, screenshots or information that would be helpful in resolving the issue.

  *  _Payment information:_ We collect certain payment and billing information when you register for certain paid Services. For example, we ask you to provide payment information, such as payment card details, which we collect via secure payment processing services.

### Information we collect automatically

We collect information about you when you use our Services, including browsing our websites and taking certain actions within the Services. This includes:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) addresses.

  * Internet Service Provider (ISP).

  * Browser type.

  * Operating system.

  * Date/time stamp.

  * Browsing actions and browsing patterns.

#### Cookies and other tracking technologies

Cookies are small text files sent by us to your computer or mobile device, which enable features and functionalities of the Services. They are unique to your account or your browser. Session-based cookies last only while your browser is open and are automatically deleted when you close your browser. Persistent cookies last until you or your browser delete them or until they expire. For example, we collect and store the following information using Cookies:

  * Authentication information: If you're signed in to our Services, cookies help us show you the right information and personalize your experience.

  * Document referrer information.

  * URL query (for example, Urchin Tracking Module (UTM) parameters).

  * Information about which variant(s) of the Services you use.

#### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses Cookies to store information. On behalf of the website provider Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to the website provider. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore, you can prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under this [link](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-US).

You can refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website: Disable Google Analytics

Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at [www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and [policies.google.com](https://policies.google.com/?hl=us). Please note that on this website, Google Analytics code is supplemented by “anonymizeIp” to ensure an anonymized collection of IP addresses (so called IP-masking).

### Information we receive from other sources

  *  _From other Service users:_ Other users of our Services may provide information about you when they submit content through the Services. We also receive your email address from other Service users when they provide it in order to invite you to the Services.

  *  _Other services you link to your account:_ We receive information about you when you or your administrator link or integrate third-party services with our Services. You should always check the privacy settings and notices in these third-party services to understand what data may be disclosed to us or shared with our Services.

## How we use the information

How we use the information we collect depends in part on which Services you use, how you use them, and any preferences you have communicated to us. Below are the specific purposes for which we use the information we collect about you:

  * To provide the Services.

  * To personalize your experience.

  * To aid in research and development.

  * To communicate with you about the Services.

  * To market, promote, and drive engagement with the Services.

  * To provide customer support.

  * To prevent fraud and abuse.

  * For any other purpose with your consent.

## How we share the information

### Sharing with other Service users

When you use the Services, we share certain information about you with other Service users.

  *  _For collaboration:_ You can create content, which may contain information about you, and grant permission to others to see, share, edit, copy and download that content based on settings you or your administrator (if applicable) select. Some collaboration features of the Services display some or all of your profile information to other Service users when you share or interact with specific content.

  *  _For use in teams and organizations:_ If you register or access the Services for use within a team and/or organization, certain information including your first name, last name, email address, profile picture, content, and account use may become accessible to that team's and/or organization's administrators and other Service users.

### Sharing with third parties

  *  _Service providers:_ We work with third-party service providers to provide website and application development, hosting, maintenance, backup, storage, infrastructure, payment processing, analysis and other services for us, which may require them to access or use information about you. If a service provider needs to access information about you to perform services on our behalf, they do so under instruction from us, including abiding by policies and procedures designed to protect your information. You can learn more about third-party service providers in the section “Nuclino Subprocessors” below.

  *  _Third-party services:_ You, your administrator or other Service users may choose to link or integrate third-party services with our Services. Doing so may give third-party apps access to your account and information about you like your name and email address, and any content you choose to use in connection with those third-party services. Third-party service policies and procedures are not controlled by us, and this privacy policy does not cover how third-party apps use your information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of third parties before connecting to or using their services to learn more about their privacy and information handling practices. If you object to information about you being shared with these third parties, please disable or remove any undesired link or integration.

  *  _With your consent:_ We share information about you with third parties when you give us consent to do so.

  *  _Compelled disclosure:_ We reserve the right to use or disclose your Personal Information if required by law or if we reasonably believe that use or disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or comply with a law, court order, or legal process.

## How we store and secure the information

### Information storage and security

We use data hosting service providers to host the information we collect, and we use technical measures to secure your data. You can learn more about services we use in the section “Nuclino Subprocessors” below. While we implement safeguards designed to protect your information, no security system is impenetrable and due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that data, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, is absolutely safe from intrusion by others. You can learn more about selected security measures [here](https://www.nuclino.com/security). We will respond to requests about information storage and security within a reasonable timeframe.

### How long we keep information

We may retain your personal information for a period of time consistent with the original purpose of collection. For instance, we may retain your personal information during the time you have an account to use the Services, and for a reasonable period of time thereafter. We also may retain your personal information during the period of time needed for Nuclino to pursue our legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## How to access and control your information

### Right to access and update information

Our Services and related documentation give you the ability to access and update certain information about you from within the Service. For example, you can access your profile information from your account and search for content containing information about you using searches in the Service. You can update your profile information within your profile settings and modify content that contains information about you using the editing tools associated with that content.

In addition to the abilities we provide from within the Services, you may request to access or update your information using the contact information at the end of this Privacy Policy. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken.

### Right to delete your information

Our Services and related documentation give you the ability to delete certain information about you from within the Service. For example, you can remove content that contains information about you using the keyword search and editing tools associated with that content and you can remove certain profile information within your profile settings.

In addition to the abilities we provide from within the Services, you may request to delete your information using the contact information at the end of this Privacy Policy. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken.

### Right to restrict information processing

In some cases, you may ask us to stop accessing, storing, using and otherwise processing your information where you believe we don't have the appropriate rights to do so.

To exercise this right, please send us your request using the contact information at the end of this Privacy Policy. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken.

### Right to data portability

Data portability is the ability to obtain some of your information in a format you can move from one service provider to another. Our Services and related documentation give you the ability to export certain information from within the Service. Should you request it by contacting us using the contact information at the end of this Privacy Policy, we will provide you with an electronic file of your basic account information and information under your sole control. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken.

## How we transfer the information we collect internationally

We collect information globally. We transfer, process, and store your information outside of your country of residence, to wherever we, Nuclino or our third-party service providers operate for the purpose of providing you the Services. Whenever we transfer your information, we take steps to protect it.

## Other important privacy-related information

### Nuclino Subprocessors

#### Infrastructure Subprocessors

Nuclino may use the following Subprocessors to host Customer Data or provide other infrastructure that helps with delivery of our Services:

Entity Name| Subprocessing Activities| Entity Country| Data Location  
---|---|---|---  
Amazon Web Services EMEA SARL| Cloud Service Provider| Luxembourg| Europe  
Heroku, Inc.| Cloud Service Provider| United States| Europe  
  
#### Other Subprocessors

Nuclino may use the following Subprocessors to perform other Service functions:

Entity Name| Subprocessing Activities| Entity Country| Data Location  
---|---|---|---  
Mailjet SAS| Cloud-based Email Service Provider| France| Europe  
FrontApp, Inc.| Cloud-based Customer Support Services| United States| United States, Europe  
Stripe, Inc.| Cloud-based Payment Processing Services| United States| United States  
Chargebee, Inc.| Cloud-based Billing and Subscription Services| United States| United States  
  
### Notice to End Users

The Services may be adopted for both personal use and use by organizations. Where the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g. your employer), that organization is the administrator of the Services and is responsible for the end-users and/or Service sites over which it has control. If this is the case, please direct your data privacy questions to your administrator, as your use of the Services is subject to that organization's policies. We are not responsible for the privacy or security practices of an administrator's organization, which may be different than this policy.

### Age limitations

To the extent prohibited by applicable law, Nuclino does not allow use of the Services by anyone younger than 16 years old. If you learn that anyone younger than 16 has unlawfully provided us with personal data, please contact us and we will take steps to delete such information.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by adding a notice on the Services homepages, login screens, or by sending you an email notification. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use the Services to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using the Services and deactivate or delete your account(s).

### Contact Us

Your information is controlled by Nuclino GmbH. If you have questions or concerns about how your information is handled, please direct your inquiry to Nuclino GmbH, as set forth below or:

 _Nuclino GmbH_  
Nymphenburger Str. 86  
80636 Munich, Germany  
Email: [contact@nuclino.com](mailto:contact@nuclino.com)
